http://www.mcw.edu/about-mcw/terms-and-privacy

President and CEO
Provost and Executive Vice President, and Dean, School of Medicine
Dean, Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences
Dean, Pharmacy School
Executive Vice President for Finance and Administration and Chief Operating Officer
Terms and Privacy
About this Website | Terms of Use, Privacy, Disclaimers, Technical Information
Thank you for visiting the website of The Medical College of Wisconsin, Inc. ("MCW"). MCW is a private, independent academic institution located at 8701 Watertown Plank Rd., P.O. Box 26509, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 53226-0509. By using the information and services on this website ("Site"), you agree to and/or acknowledge our General Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, European Economic Area Privacy Disclosures, Proprietary Rights, Video and Other Rich Media Disclaimer, Technical Information and Mobile App Disclaimer.
The Medical College of Wisconsin strives to comply with copyright and intellectual property laws and regulations. If you have a question or comment concerning this Site or any materials included in this Site, please notify us at the following address:
Medical College of Wisconsin
Office of Communications
8701 Watertown Plank Rd.
Milwaukee, WI 53226-0509
(414) 955-6166 (fax)
Further Detail
all
General Terms of Use
By using the information and services on this website ("Site"), you agree to these General Terms of Use ("Terms") and all applicable laws and regulations.
MCW has the right to change the terms of this policy at any time and without prior notice.
Some departments, programs, institutes and centers of MCW maintain Web pages that may contain specific disclaimers and copyright notices that apply directly to the information contained on those pages. Those disclaimers and copyright notices do not restrict or limit these Terms, but rather emphasize and amplify applicable laws and regulations pertaining to information on those Web pages.
Material on this Site is provided for informational, educational and research purposes only. Scientific information on this Site is provided to enhance knowledge and encourage progress in the scientific community.
Use of material on this Site for commercial purposes represents an infringement of MCW's copyright and intellectual property rights. (See General Copyright Notice below.)
The intended audiences of this Site include the general public, patients, prospective and current medical and graduate students, medical residents, researchers, health professionals, financial contributors and grantors, faculty members, alumni and MCW employees. Some Web pages serve specific audiences and may be password-protected. Access to some pages may be otherwise restricted.
This Site, its services and materials, including text, graphics, images, logos and links, programming code, and software, are provided on an "as is" basis, and MCW makes no claims or warranties of any kind, whether express or implied with respect to any Web page, service or material.
MCW does not maintain that information contained herein is, in every respect, accurate, adequate or complete. While MCW makes reasonable efforts to provide accurate and up-to-date information, MCW is not responsible for any errors, omissions, and/or outcomes resulting from the use of this information. You are encouraged to confirm the information contained herein with the originating sources.
Where appropriate, information contained on this Site is supported by clear references to source data in the peer-reviewed literature. MCW seeks to provide unbiased, balanced information. Please consult your own physician regarding the applicability of any opinions or recommendations with respect to your symptoms or medical condition or the applicability of research information. Scientific or research data should be verified with the originating sources.
This Site contains links and references to other sites, products and services offered by third parties. These are provided for your convenience and reference only and do not constitute an endorsement or approval by MCW. MCW does not assume any liability for your use of those sites, their products, services or information. If you access documents on other websites, you are subject to the privacy policies, terms and conditions of those websites.
MCW's physicians and employees provide patient care services at hospitals, clinics and community agencies, which may have their own websites. While these institutions and agencies have affiliations or working arrangements with MCW, MCW does not operate or sponsor their sites, or have any jurisdiction over their privacy or operational policies. References or links to those sites are provided for your convenience. MCW does not assume any responsibility for information provided on those sites. Should the MCW Site be down for any length of time, MCW does not assume any responsibility for lost information.
All information about the users of this Site – including their email addresses – is confidential. MCW does not – and will not – sell or redistribute the list of users or subscribers to anyone.
Indemnity
By using this Site, you agree to indemnify and hold harmless the Medical College of Wisconsin, its individual departments, programs, institutes and centers, its administrators, faculty, staff, employees, agents and Trustees from any and all claims and damages relating to any charges or demands arising from your use of this Site.
General Copyright Notice
The MCW Site contains copyrighted material, trademarks and other information owned by MCW and protected under the United States copyright and trademark laws. MCW requires all users of this Site to comply with all state and federal laws, including copyright laws.
You may download, print, reproduce, or use materials displayed on this Site for noncommercial, educational, personal or research purposes only, provided that you do not alter the content or any trademark, logo, copyright, author's name or author's identity. The posting date of the material on the Site must accompany such copied material. Reprinted materials (for educational, research or personal use) must contain the following attribution: "Reprinted by permission of Medical College of Wisconsin, (with Site publication date.)"
Note that this Site contains copyrighted work created under contract with government agencies, foundations, funding organizations and commercial companies, etc. If a particular author places further restrictions on the material, you must honor those restrictions regardless of whether such restrictions are described on this Site.
By using any of this material, you assume all risks of copyright infringement and related liability.
The contents of this Site may not be used for commercial purposes, without prior written permission of MCW. To obtain permission to reproduce information on this Site, submit the specifics of your request in writing to:
Medical College of Wisconsin
Office of Communications
8701 Watertown Plank Rd.
Milwaukee, WI 53226
(414) 955-6166 (fax)
The Medical College of Wisconsin strives to comply with copyright and intellectual property laws and regulations. If you have a question or comment concerning this Site or any materials included in this Site, please notify the Office of Communications, Medical College of Wisconsin, 8701 Watertown Plank Rd., Milwaukee, WI 53226-0509.
Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for www.mcw.edu,
the main Medical College of Wisconsin (MCW) website. Please note that MCW Schools, Centers, Departments and other MCW units and affiliates may have separate privacy policies. By using this website, you are consenting to our collection and use of information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
What information do we gather about you?
We and our third-party vendors collect certain information regarding your use of www.mcw.edu  such as your IP address and browser type. Your session and the pages you visit on www.mcw.edu will be tracked, but you will remain anonymous. We may use your IP address to identify the general geographic area from which you are accessing www.mcw.edu We connect data from different systems but do not link IP addresses to any personal information. We may also collect other information as described in this policy.
What do we use your information for?
We use the information we gather from you for systems administration purposes, systems or data abuse prevention, to track user trends, and for the other purposes described in this policy. If you send us an email, the email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions. We will not share, sell, rent, swap, or authorize any third party to use your email address for commercial purposes without your permission.
User information may be shared with third-party vendors to the extent necessary to provide and improve web services or other communications to users. For example, we use third parties such as Google Analytics and other tools to generate reports on site usage, web traffic, user behavior, and user interests in order to optimize our website for our visitors. We also use geographic, demographic, and interest-based reports of our website visitors to create custom audience lists. We prohibit any third parties who receive user information for this purpose from using or sharing user information for any purpose other than providing services for the benefit of our users.
We may also provide your information to third parties in circumstances where we believe that doing so is necessary or appropriate to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request; detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; or protect our rights and safety and the rights and safety of our users or others.
How is this information collected and how can you opt out?
Google and other third parties may use cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect or receive information from this website and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target ads. For more information on Google Analytics, consult their terms of use, privacy practices, and ads settings. You can opt out of the collection and use of this information through tools like the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.
Cookies
Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer (unless you block them). We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. You may disable cookies through your individual browser options or you can opt out of the collection and use of this information through tools like the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.
Other Websites and Cookies
This website may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.
Cookies may be set by parties other than us. These “third-party cookies” may, for example, originate from websites such as YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, Soundcloud, or other social media services for which www.mcw.edu has implemented “plug-ins.” Since the cookie policies of these sites change over time, you should determine their policies by visiting the privacy policy pages of these sites directly.
Information Protection
This site has reasonable security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure.
Users Located in the European Economic Area
If you are located in the European Union, Iceland, Liechtenstein or Norway (the “European Economic Area”), please see the next section of this web page for additional information about ways that certain MCW and its Schools, Centers, Departments, units and controlled entities, including this website, may collect, use, and share information about you.
Changes to this Policy
This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page.
Effective Date
The effective date of this policy is December 15, 2018.
European Economic Area Privacy Disclosures
The following EEA privacy disclosures (the “Disclosures”) provide information about the collection, use, processing and sharing of data about individuals located in the European Union, Iceland, Liechtenstein or Norway (the “European Economic Area” or “EEA”).
In these Disclosures,
“GDPR” means the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation;
“Personal Data” means information that relates to an individual who is directly or indirectly identified or identifiable;
“EEA Processing Activities” means the collection, use, processing or sharing of Personal Data when those activities are within the scope of the GDPR.
These Disclosures apply only to the use of Personal Data in EEA Processing Activities.
Further, these Disclosures apply only to the Medical College of Wisconsin, Inc. and its Schools, Centers, Departments and other MCW units and controlled entities (collectively, “MCW Entities”) that link to these Disclosures or expressly adopt them in writing.
In these Disclosures the words “we” or “our” refer to each such MCW Entity.
In some cases a MCW Entity may provide other information about its EEA Processing Activities in its own supplemental or separate disclosures.
These Disclosures apply to EEA Processing Activities by any means, including hardcopy (such as paper applications or forms) and electronic means (such as websites and mobile applications).
A.	How We Collect and Use Personal Data
We collect several categories of Personal Data in circumstances that may involve EEA Processing Activities, including data you provide, data collected automatically (potentially including location data), and data we obtain from third party sources.
We use the Personal Data that we collect to carry on various institutional, administrative, educational or research activities.
As described in more detail below, we rely on a number of legal bases to lawfully process your Personal Data.
The ways in which we collect and use your Personal Data vary depending on the relationship between you and us, as well as the MCW Entity with which you interact.
The following sections of these Disclosures describe in more detail how we collect and use Personal Data in various circumstances that may involve EEA Processing Activities.
Please note that, depending on the situation, some of the processing of Personal Data we do in the various circumstances described below may not fall within the scope of the GDPR.
1.
Personal Data We Obtain from You
Websites and Mobile Applications
As is true of most digital platforms, we gather certain data automatically when you use one of our websites or mobile applications, such as your IP address, browser type and device type.
Certain web-forms also collect Personal Data you provide, for example when you enter the data into form fields on a feedback page.
If we also process data through our websites or mobile applications for one of the activities described further below, those sections will provide additional information about how data are collected and used.
We and our third-party vendors collect Personal Data for the primary purposes or conducting analytics, responding to your requests and providing you with relevant information.
Admissions and Financial Aid
We collect and use various kinds of Personal Data when you apply for admission to a School, program or course offered by us, and when you seek financial aid, if available.
The primary source of these data is your application.
We may solicit additional data, for example, from interviewers as part of the admissions process, if applicable, or from other available sources when identifying potential candidates for admission in connection with recruiting activities.
The Personal Data collected by us, or on our behalf, during the admissions process is collected for the primary purposes of considering your candidacy for admission to the relevant School, program or course, evaluating your eligibility for financial aid, if applicable, and, if you are admitted and enroll, facilitating your education (such as by sharing Personal Data with registrars and others in order to enable your enrollment and participation in the School, program or course to which you have been admitted).
Alumni and Donors
We collect and use various kinds of Personal Data about alumni, donors and prospective donors from a number of sources, including data you provide to us, for example, when you update your alumni or donor profile, connect with us on social media, complete a donation form or register to attend MCW events.
If you were a student or studied at MCW, some of your Personal Data are transferred from your student record into our alumni databases.
We may also collect Personal Data from publicly available sources or third-party sources that support our operations.
The Personal Data collected by us, or on our behalf, is collected for the primary purpose of providing you opportunities to engage with MCW, alumni, donors, prospective donors and students through interactions, events and your gifts or donations.
We may disclose your data to other MCW affiliated entities and individuals such as alumni clubs and special interest groups (SIGS) or volunteers when their work meets one of the purposes described below.
Online Education
We and our third-party vendors collect your Personal Data when you apply or register for online education offerings.
Further Personal Data collection occurs upon enrollment for courses or programs and throughout your online education interactions.
In some cases, our collection of Personal Data from you in connection with online education activities takes place as part of a “hybrid” program in which you also may participate in person.
The Personal Data collected by us, or on our behalf, are collected for the primary purpose of providing online education courses and programs, and, if applicable, evaluating qualification for online education certificates or credit.
Employees and Job Applicants
We collect your Personal Data when you apply to work for us.
Further Personal Data collection occurs at hiring and throughout your employment relationship with us.
The Personal Data collected by us, or on our behalf, are collected for the primary purpose of providing employment or enabling authorized persons to utilize our services and facilities.
Research
Our researchers and affiliates may collect, use and share your Personal Data as part of a research study in which you have agreed to participate as a research subject or researcher, or in which your existing data are used.
Most often, before any Personal Data are collected for research purposes, you will be provided a consent and/or authorization form relating to the specific research project that explains the types of data collected and the purposes for which such data are processed and shared.
In such a case, the description of the collection and use of your Personal Data provided in the consent and/or authorization form will replace the information provided here.
The Personal Data collected by our researchers and affiliates, or on their behalf, is collected for the primary purpose of furthering research and understanding in fields of academic study.
In certain research studies, we may ask to collect on-line information from you to help us determine your eligibility for the study. Additional information on how we collect and use this information may be found at “Information for Potential Research Volunteers Who Complete Medical College of Wisconsin (“MCW”) On-Line Web Forms (PDF).”
Examples of Personal Data that may be collected for research purposes are contact and demographic information, data revealing racial or ethnic origin, data concerning your health, sex, or sexual orientation, genetic data, and biometric data. Not every research study will collect each of these types of data.
If you have questions about the processing of your data in connection with a research study, you should contact the MCW personnel who are conducting the research or the contact persons named in any consent form you signed when you joined the study.
2.
Personal Data We Obtain from Third Party Sources
As part of our EEA Processing Activities, we may obtain certain Personal Data about you from third party sources, which we may use for the purposes and in the ways described in “How We Collect and Use Personal Data” above and in “Additional Uses of Personal Data” below.
In some cases, we may obtain your consent for additional uses.
Partners and Service Providers
We use partners and service providers, such as application facilitators including the Common Application, the American Medical College Application Service (AMCAS) ® and the Pharmacy College Application Service (PharmCAS).
We also use payment processors (for example, CyberSource) and analytics providers (for example, Qualtrics), to perform services on our behalf.
Some of these partners have access to Personal Data about you that we may not otherwise have (for example, when you sign up directly with that provider) and may share some or all of these data with us.
Single Sign-On
Some of our online services or research activities may allow you to register and login to those services through a third-party platform.
When you login to our service through a third-party platform, you allow us to access and collect any Personal Data from your third-party platform account permitted under the settings and privacy statement of that platform.
Supplemental Personal Data
We may receive additional Personal Data from third-party sources, such as public or private databases (for example, compilations of email or postal addresses), or companies or institutions that may sponsor or facilitate your participation in one of our programs, which we may also append to existing Personal Data.
3.
Additional Uses of Personal Data
In addition to the uses described above, including under “Personal Data We Obtain from You” and “Personal Data We Obtain from Third Party Sources,” we may use your Personal Data for the following purposes.
These additional uses may under certain circumstances be based on your consent, may be necessary to fulfill our contractual commitments to you, may be necessary for legal compliance, or are necessary to serve our legitimate interest in the following operations:
Conducting our operations and administering our educational offerings;
Administering fellowships, grants and other programs in support of individual study and research projects;
Contacting you to respond to your requests or inquiries;
Providing you with newsletters, articles, service alerts or announcements, event invitations, and other information that we believe may be of interest to you;
Requesting gifts and donations;
At your request, processing and fulfilling transactions for merchandise or other MCW products;
Alerting you about a safety or security announcement;
Conducting research, surveys and similar inquiries to help us understand trends and needs of our applicants, students and others using our websites or other services;
Meeting the requirements of our accreditors;
Disclosing directory information as described in MCW’s Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) Policy;
Performing marketing, promotions and advertising, either directly or through third-parties.
These activities may include interest-based advertising, targeted advertising and online behavioral advertising in order to increase the likelihood that the content would be of interest to you;
Preventing, investigating, taking action regarding or providing notice of fraud, unlawful or criminal activity, other misconduct, security or technical issues, or unauthorized access to or use of Personal Data, our website or data systems; or
Responding to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process; enforcing our agreements; protecting the health, safety, rights or property of you, us or others; and meeting legal obligations.
4.
Legitimate Interests
We rely on several legitimate interests in using and sharing your Personal Data.
These interests include:
Providing, improving and customizing our educational offerings;
Administration of our operations;
Promoting the success of our current and former students;
Furthering research and understanding in fields of academic study;
Maintaining an ongoing relationship with alumni, donors and prospective donors, and helping to connect them with others;
Requesting gifts or donations;
Offering attendance to events and opportunities to volunteer;
Conducting admissions research;
Understanding how our online platforms are being used;
Exploring ways to develop and grow our operations;
Ensuring the safety and security of our students, faculty, fellows, employees and others;
Cybersecurity;
Enhancing protection against fraud, spam, harassment, intellectual property infringement, crime and security risks; and
Meeting our obligations and enforcing our legal rights.
5.
Data Retention
We will retain your Personal Data for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in these Disclosures unless a longer period is required under applicable law, or is needed to resolve disputes or protect our legal rights or otherwise to comply with legal obligations.
Where we are processing Personal Data based on our legitimate interests, we generally will retain the data for a reasonable period of time based on the particular interest, taking into account the fundamental interests and the rights and freedoms of the data subjects.
Where we are processing Personal Data based on your consent, we generally will retain the information for the period of time necessary to carry out the processing activities to which you consented, subject to your right, under certain circumstances, to have certain of your Personal Data erased (see “Your Rights” below).
Where we are processing Personal Data based on contract, we generally will retain the information for the duration of the contract plus some additional limited period of time that is necessary to comply with law or that represents the statute of limitations for legal claims that could arise from the contractual relationship.
Where we are processing Personal Data based on the public interest, we generally retain the information for the period of time that continues to serve that underlying interest.
B.	How We Share and Disclose Personal Data
We share your Personal Data with third parties in the ways described in these Disclosures.
We may share your Personal Data with third parties as described in the “How We Collect and Use Personal Data” section above, as well as between MCW Entities.
Additionally, we may share information as described below:
Service Providers
We share your Personal Data with third-party service providers that complete transactions or perform services on our behalf or for your benefit, such as:
Payment and contribution processing;
Customer relationship management services;
Marketing and analytics;
Processing admissions applications;
Alumni and donor outreach and engagement;
Event registration and coordination;
Providing course platforms or tools that enable or enhance our offerings;
Course registration and administration;
Course evaluations and assessments;
Enrollment verification;
Research insights and analytics;
Research collaboration;
Educational operations and collaborations;
Performing human resources administration; and
System maintenance and security.
Partners
We may share your Personal Data with other institutions for the purposes of administering programs and services, such as:
Cross-registration for courses and events with other universities;
Course registration and administration;
Course evaluations and assessments;
Study at other universities including study abroad at foreign universities;
Online education offerings through online platforms;
Research arrangements with other universities or partners; and
Events and activities of MCW-affiliated clubs and special interest groups.
Third-Party Mobile App Providers
With your knowledge and consent, our services on your mobile device may gather and transfer your Personal Data, including location information, from and to other applications, functions and tools within your mobile device if you use our mobile applications.
Social Media Platforms
We may also use services provided by third parties (such as social media platforms) to serve targeted ads or sponsored content on third-party platforms.
For more information regarding our use of cookies and similar technologies, see the “Cookies and Similar Technologies” section below.
Legal Process, Safety and Terms Enforcement
We may disclose your Personal Data to legal or government regulatory authorities as required by applicable law.
We also disclose your Personal Data to third parties as required by applicable law in connection with claims, disputes or litigation, when otherwise required by applicable law, or if we determine its disclosure is necessary to protect the health, safety, rights or property of you, us or others, or to enforce our legal rights or contractual commitments that you have made.
C.	International Data Transfers
MCW may transfer your Personal Data between MCW Entities and/or to the third parties discussed above.
We may transfer your Personal Data outside the EEA relying on appropriate or suitable safeguards or specific derogations recognized under data protection laws, including the GDPR.
The European Commission has adopted standard data protection clauses, which provide safeguards for Personal Data transferred outside of the EEA.
We may use Standard Contractual Clauses when transferring Personal Data from a country in the EEA to a country outside the EEA.
If your Personal Data are affected, you can request a copy of our Standard Contractual Clauses by contacting us as set forth in the Contact Us section below.
D.	Cookies and Similar Technologies
We may collect Personal Data about you, or information that becomes Personal Data if combined with other information, when you visit or use our websites and online services.
This information may be collected through the use of cookies, which are small data files placed on your computer or mobile device that allow us to collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with our websites or online services.
Some of these cookies are managed by us (first-party cookies), while others are managed by third parties that we do not control (third-party cookies).
This information may also be collected through the use of other data collection technologies (such as web beacons, pixels or tags) that embed graphic files in our websites and online services.
These graphic files contain a unique identifier that enables us to recognize when someone has visited our website or online services, or in the case of web beacons, opened an email that we have sent them.
These small data files or graphic files serve various functions:
Strictly Necessary: Necessary to deliver our services;
Performance and Functionality: Enhance the performance and functionality of our services but are non-essential to their use;
Analytics and Customization: Allow us to understand the effectiveness of our services and marketing campaigns, as well as to customize our services based on this information; or
Advertising: Make advertising messages more relevant to you and your interests.
You can control the use of certain cookies and similar technologies by:
Opting out of targeted online advertising through advertising networks (please visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices/, http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/ or http://www.youronlinechoices.com for more information);
Setting or amending your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies (please visit your browser’s help menu for more information).
If you choose to reject certain cookies and similar technologies, you may still use our websites and online services though your access to some functionality and features may be restricted.
If you have any questions regarding our use of cookies and other similar technologies, please contact us as set forth in the “Contact Us” section below.
E. Your Rights
We will provide you upon your reasonable, good faith request with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Data as part of our EEA Processing Activities, to the extent required by and in accordance with applicable law.
In certain cases, you may also have a right, with respect to your Personal Data collected and used in the EEA Processing Activities, to:
correct or update any of your Personal Data that is inaccurate;
to restrict or limit the ways in which we use your Personal Data;
to object to the processing of your Personal Data;
to request the deletion of your Personal Data; and
to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in an easily accessible format.
To submit a request, please send an email message to compliance@mcw.edu.
Because we want to avoid taking action regarding your Personal Data at the direction of someone other than you, we will ask you for information verifying your identity.
We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
You also have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Data as part of the EEA Processing Activities, where our processing is solely based on your consent, subject to certain limitations at law.
In some cases, you can do this by discontinuing use of the services involved in the EEA Processing Activities.
This would include by closing all of your online accounts with us and contacting us at compliance@mcw.edu to request that your Personal Data be deleted.
If you withdraw your consent to the use or sharing of your Personal Data for the purposes set out in these Disclosures or the other MCW privacy statements that link to or expressly adopt these Disclosures, you may not have access to all (or any) of the related services, and we might not be able to provide you all (or any) of the services.
Please note that, in certain cases, we may continue to process your Personal Data after you have withdrawn consent and requested that we delete your Personal Data, if we have a legal basis to do so.
For example, we may retain certain data if we need to do so to comply with an independent legal obligation, if we still need the data for the lawful purposes for which we obtained the data, or if it is necessary to do so to pursue our legitimate interest in keeping our services and operations safe and secure.
If you have any complaints regarding our privacy practices, you have the right to make a complaint with your national data protection authority (i.e., supervisory authority).
F.	User Generated Content
Some of our services involved in EEA Processing Activities may enable users to submit their own content.
Unless otherwise indicated, please remember that any Personal Data you submit or post as user-generated content could become public information.
You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information in such submissions or posts.
We cannot prevent others from using that information in a manner that may violate these Disclosures, the law or your personal privacy and safety.
We are not responsible for the results of such postings.
G.	Updates to the Disclosures
We may update these Disclosures from time to time without prior notice by posting revised Disclosures to this site.
You can determine when these Disclosures were last revised by checking the Last Updated date in these Disclosures.
H.	Contact Us
If you have any questions, comments, requests or concerns about these Disclosures or other privacy-related matters, you may contact us in the following ways:
Email: compliance@mcw.edu
Mailing Address:
Corporate Compliance Office
Medical College of Wisconsin
8701 Watertown Plank Rd.
Milwaukee, WI 53226
Effective Date:
May 25, 2018
Last Updated:
December 15, 2018
Proprietary Rights
The College has trademarks or joint trademarks on the following logos used on this Site.
These trademarked logos may not be used without the prior written permission of the Medical College of Wisconsin.
Owners of other sites may link to the Medical College of Wisconsin Site with prior permission. To obtain permission, submit the specifics of your request in writing to:
Medical College of Wisconsin
Office of Communications
8701 Watertown Plank Rd.
Milwaukee, WI 53226
(414) 955-6166 (fax)
A condition of permission is your agreement to remove such link upon request from the Medical College of Wisconsin.
Logo Standards
The logos on this website reflect the Medical College of Wisconsin's strong affiliations with Froedtert Hospital and Children's Hospital and Health System.
Our identity is vital to our success
The identity of the Medical College of Wisconsin influences opinions, attitudes and decision-making. For this reason, we have adopted identity standards to present a strong, clear and unified identity.
The basic standards and guidelines of the Medical College of Wisconsin's Identity Standards are available to staff via the College's intranet. The consistent use of these standards helps to represent the Medical College of Wisconsin as an institution of strength, high quality and integrity.
Medical College of Wisconsin employees may use the Intranet website from their office computers.
Contact Us About Questions on Use of Logos
If you have questions on how to use official logos for the Medical College of Wisconsin, Medical College Physicians or affiliations between the Medical College and Froedtert Hospital and the College and Children's Specialty Group, please contact the following:
Medical College of Wisconsin/Office of Communications
(414) 955-4725 | (414) 955-6166 (fax)
mcwlogo@mcw.edu
www.mcw.edu
Video and Other Rich Media Disclaimer
This video/audio file is owned by the Medical College of Wisconsin. Any copying or distribution is prohibited without our express written consent.
This multimedia program was developed by the Medical College of Wisconsin for the private use of individuals who are authorized to view its contents.
The Medical College of Wisconsin presents the information on the video/audio presentation as an educational service. While the information on this presentation is about health care issues, it is not medical advice. People seeking specific medical advice or assistance should contact their personal physician.
Although we believe the information in this presentation to be accurate and timely, because of the rapid advances in health care and our reliance on information provided by outside sources, we make no warranty or guarantee concerning the accuracy or reliability of the content or other material which we may reference. When clinical matters are discussed, the opinions presented are those of the discussants only.
The material discussed on the presentation is not intended to present the only or necessarily the best method or procedure, but rather presents the approach or opinion of the discussant. This presentation is provided in an “as is” format without warranties of any kind, expressed or implied, including but not limited to warranties of title, non-infringement or implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose.
Any questions concerning the content of this program may be direction to the Medical College of Wisconsin at webmaster@mcw.edu or (414) 955-8296.
Technical Information
Contact Information:
Contact webmaster@mcw.edu to comment or inquire about this website, or (414) 955-4725.
Java and other plug-ins:
Our website uses Java code for menu navigation. Update or install the latest Java plug-in:
Windows
Mac
Additional plug-ins to improve your experience of our website include:
Adobe Acrobat Reader
Macromedia Flash Player
Video streaming, podcasting and other media are posted by some MCW departments. Additional software, such as a video and/or audio players and plug-ins, may be required to view rich media.
Website Awards
In 2004 the Medical College of Wisconsin website received the Award of Excellence by the Association of American Medical Colleges.
Website Updates
Updates to the www.mcw.edu website are made every day. You are encouraged to visit often. To receive email updates whenever significant changes to the Medical College website are made, please contact the webmaster@mcw.edu.
Mobile App Disclaimer
Terms and Conditions
MOBILE APP– Terms and Conditions (“Terms”) updated November 2018
PLEASE READ THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE CAREFULLY BEFORE USING OUR MOBILE DEVICE SERVICE.
The Medical College of Wisconsin, Inc., is a Wisconsin, non-profit educational and research corporation with its principal offices at 8701 Watertown Plank Road, Milwaukee, Wisconsin 53226 USA (“we” or “us”), provides you with the NeuroMapper App (the “App”) under these Terms and Conditions (this “Agreement”). The App is referred to as the “Service.” As used in these Terms and Conditions, ‘you’ or ‘users’ refers to individuals using the Service.
By using the Service and/or by clicking the “I Agree” button, you unconditionally agree to follow and be bound by this Agreement. If you do not agree to be bound by and comply with all of the terms of this Agreement, you may not use our Service.
Intended Users
The Service is available only to users who are at least 18 years old and qualified healthcare professionals. You may not provide access to or use the Service or Content (as defined below) thereof for the benefit of third parties or make commercial use of the Service or related Content, but you may use the Service for your personal use subject to this Agreement. Use of and access to the Service is void where prohibited. By accessing and using the Service, you shall ensure that (a) any and all registration information you submit is truthful and accurate; (b) you will maintain the accuracy of such information; (c) your use of the Service will comply with and does not violate any applicable law, regulation, order or guideline and (d) you consent to receiving messages and promotional material offering in-Service purchases.
Modifications of this Agreement
We reserve the right to update or modify this Agreement at any time. By continuing to use the Service after any such changes, you agree to follow and be bound by this Agreement as changed. For these reasons, we encourage you to periodically review this Agreement.
Disclaimers
Your use of any aspect of the Service is at your own risk. You must consult with healthcare providers and make your medical decisions based on their advice.
MCW IS NOT PROVIDING ANY MEDICAL ADVICE OF ANY KIND. WE MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES WHATSOEVER IN RESPECT OF THE SERVICE. INFORMATION REGARDING MEDICATIONS, HEALTH, MEDICAL ADVICE AND OTHERWISE MAY BE PROVIDED BY THIRD PARTIES, INCLUDING OTHER USERS OF THE SERVICE. WE CANNOT ACCEPT ANY LIABILITY WHATSOEVER IN RESPECT OF ANY SUCH CONTENT WHICH IS PROVIDED BY THIRD PARTIES AND/OR ANY OTHER USERS OF THE SERVICE. ANY ACTIONS YOU TAKE BASED ON CONTENT, NOTIFICATIONS AND OTHERWISE PROVIDED BY THE SERVICE ARE TAKEN AT YOUR SOLE RISK. A. YOU SHOULD ALWAYS CHECK ANY INFORMATION PROVIDED THROUGH THE SERVICE TO ENSURE ITS ACCURACY
We will investigate suspected violations of this Agreement or illegal and inappropriate behavior through the Service. Please note that we will fully cooperate with any law enforcement investigation or court order ordering us or directing us to disclose the identity, behavior or activities of anyone believed to have violated this Agreement or to have engaged in illegal behavior.
You may request termination of your account at any time and for any reason and you may exercise your rights according to the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), by sending an email to info@MCW.com. More information about your rights pertaining to the GDPR can be found at https://eugdpr.org. Any suspension or termination of your account shall not affect your obligations to us under this Agreement (including but not limited to ownership and limitation of liability), including all those obligations, which by their sense and context are intended to survive the suspension or termination of your account.
Technology; Support
We do not warrant or guarantee that the Service will function with your mobile or computing device or be compatible with the hardware or software on any particular devices. Information will be transmitted over a medium that will be beyond our control and jurisdiction; multiple factors, including network availability, may affect alert or notification delivery or otherwise interfere with the operation of the Service.
Without limiting the foregoing, we, our licensors, and our suppliers make no representations or warranties about (1) the availability, accuracy, reliability, completeness, quality, performance, suitability or timeliness of the Service, Content, including software, text, graphics, links, or communications provided on or through the use of the Service; or (2) the satisfaction of any government regulations requiring disclosure of information on prescription drug products or the approval or compliance of any software tools with regard to the Service.
We have no obligation to provide technical support or maintenance for the Service.
Although we take reasonable measures to keep the Service free of viruses, worms, Trojan horses or other code that contain destructive properties, we do not warrant or guarantee that files available for downloading through the Service will be free of such contaminations.
User’s Responsibilities
If you submit any information to us through or related to the Service or send us any business information, feedback, idea, concept or invention to us by email, you shall ensure that such information is not confidential and that you have all necessary permission to submit or otherwise make available such information.
You further agree that:
you will not reproduce, duplicate, copy, sell, resell, or exploit the Service, its Content, its software or any portion of any of the foregoing;
you will not use the Service for any purpose in violation of local, state, national or international laws;
you will not solicit another person’s password or personal information under false pretenses;
you will not impersonate another person or entity or otherwise misrepresent your affiliation with a person or entity, and/or use or access another user’s account or password without permission;
you will not violate the legal rights of others, including defaming, abuse, stalking or threatening users;
you will not infringe the intellectual property rights, privacy rights, or moral rights of any third party;
you will not post or transmit any Content that is (or you reasonably believe or should reasonably believe to be) illegal, fraudulent, or unauthorized, or furthers such activity, or that involves (or you reasonably believe or should reasonably believe to involve) any stolen, illegal, counterfeit, fraudulent, pirated, or unauthorized material;
you will not publish falsehoods or misrepresentations, including with respect to any medical or health information; and
you will not post or transmit any Content that is (or reasonably should be understood to be) libelous, defamatory, obscene, offensive (including material promoting or glorifying hate, violence, or bigotry or otherwise inappropriate to the community ethos of the Service).
You agree not to interfere or attempt to interfere with the proper working of the Service or to disrupt the operations or violate the security of the Service. Violations of system or network operation or security may result in civil or criminal liability. We will investigate possible occurrences of such violations, and we may involve and cooperate with law enforcement authorities in prosecuting anyone involved with such violations. You agree to comply with all user responsibilities and obligations as stated in this Agreement. Non-enforcement or our failure to act with respect to a breach by you or others of this Agreement does not constitute consent or waiver, and we reserve the right to enforce such term at our sole discretion. No waiver of any breach or default hereunder shall be deemed to be a waiver of any preceding or subsequent breach or default. Nothing contained in this Agreement shall be construed to limit the actions or remedies available to us with respect to any prohibited activity or conduct.
5.	License
We grant, and you hereby accept, a restricted, non-exclusive, non-transferable license to use the App for academic, research and internal business purposes only, without a fee as set forth within this Agreement.
Under this license, except as and only to the extent any of the following restrictions are prohibited by applicable law or any of the restricted activities are permitted by the licensing terms of any open-sourced components incorporated into the App, you may not:
lend, rent, lease, sell, redistribute, assign, sublicense or otherwise transfer the App or the right to download or use the App;
use the Service for any commercial purpose. Commercial use includes: (1) integration of all or part of the Service into a product for sale, lease or license by or on your behalf to third parties, or (2) distribution of Service to third parties that need it to commercialize product sold or licensed by you or on your behalf.
Should you have a need for commercial use of the Service, commercial licensing may be available upon making a specific request to the Medical College of Wisconsin, Inc, for the purpose of generating a customized license agreement.
use the Service for any commercial or non-commercial public display;
copy, decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, attempt to derive the source code of the App, any App updates, or any part of the App or updates, or attempt to do any of the foregoing;
copy, modify or create derivative works of the Service, Documentation any Service or Documentation updates or any part of the Service, Documentation or updates;
remove any copyright or other proprietary notices from the App, Documentation, part of the App or from the Site;
transfer the Content or materials from the App or Site to anyone else or “mirror” the same on any server;
circumvent, disable, or otherwise interfere with security-related features of the Service or features that prevent or restrict
use or copying of any content;
use any robot, spider, site search or retrieval Service, or any other manual or automatic device or process to retrieve, index,
data-mine, or in any way reproduce or circumvent the navigational structure or presentation of the Service;
harvest, collect or mine information about other users of the Service;
post or transmit any virus, worm Trojan horse or other harmful or disruptive element; or
violate any applicable law, rule or regulation.
If you violate any of these restrictions, the license will automatically terminate, and you may be subject to prosecution and damages.
6.	Ownership
MCW and its licensors own the Documentation and App, including any material or Content made available through the Service, including our proprietary algorithm, and all worldwide intellectual property rights in the foregoing. Except as expressly permitted herein, you may not copy, further develop, reproduce, re-publish, modify, alter download, post, broadcast, transmit or otherwise use any material made available in the Service. You will not remove, alter or conceal any copyright, trademark, service mark or other proprietary rights notices incorporated in the Service. All trademarks are trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective owners. Nothing in this Agreement grants you any right to use any trademark, service mark, logo, or trade name of ours or any third party.
7.	Feedback and Citation
In exchange for the non-exclusive license granted herein, you will provide feedback, to us.
Such feedback may be requested by us upon reasonable notice and through ordinary channels of communication.
If the Service is used to obtain a result, and that result is published in scientific or public literature, then you agree to acknowledge your use of the Services in an appropriate citation.
At a minimum, the citation should include:
The name of the App: NeuroMapper
The source of the App: The Medical College of Wisconsin, Inc.
The authors of the App: David Sabsevitz, PhD
8.	Apple, Inc.
This provision only applies in respect of the version of the App used on devices of Apple, Inc. This Agreement is an agreement between you and us. Apple has no responsibility for the App or the content of the App, including in respect of claims of intellectual property infringement, product liability or that the App does not conform with applicable law. To the maximum extent permitted by applicable law, Apple provides no warranty in respect of the App and has no obligation to provide support in respect of the App. All claims in respect of the App must be directed to us and not to Apple. Your use of the App must be in compliance with the App Store Terms of Service, and you may only use the App on an iPhone or iPod that you own or control as permitted by such terms. In the event the App fails to conform to the warranty set forth herein, you may notify Apple, and Apple will refund the purchase price for the App to you. Apple shall be a third party beneficiary of this Agreement with the right to enforce this Agreement against you.
9.	Infringement
We accept no responsibility or liability for any material provided or posted by a user, at his solely discretion. We will make a reasonable effort to monitor and moderate the content posted by users for any obvious illegal content. If you believe that something appearing on the Service infringes your copyright, you may send us a notice requesting that it be removed, or access to it blocked. We suggest that you consult your legal advisor before filing a notice or counter-notice. Be aware that there can be substantial penalties for false claims. It is our policy to terminate the accounts of repeat infringers in appropriate circumstances. Send notices and counter-notices to info@MCW.com.
10.	Export Restriction
Except as authorized by U.S. law and the laws of the jurisdiction in which the Service was obtained or is used, you may not use, export or re-export the Service. Specifically, and without limiting the foregoing, the Service may not be exported or re-exported into any U.S. or Israel embargoed countries or to anyone on the U.S. Department of Commerce Denied Person’s List or Entity List or the U.S. Treasury Department’s list of Specially Designated Nationals. You represent and warrant that you are not on any such list or located in any such country and that you will not use the Service for any purposes prohibited by U.S. or other applicable law.
11.	Termination
This Agreement is effective until terminated by either you or us. You may terminate this Agreement at any time, provided that you discontinue any further use of the Service. If you violate this Agreement, our permission to you to use the Service automatically terminates. We may, in our sole discretion, terminate this Agreement and your access to any or all of the Service, at any time and for any reason, after notifying you, without penalty or liability to you or any third party. In the event of your breach of this Agreement, these actions are in addition to and not in lieu or limitation of any other right or remedy that may be available to us. Upon any termination of the Agreement by either you or us, you must promptly uninstall the App on all of your devices and destroy all materials downloaded or otherwise obtained from the Service, all Documentation, and all copies of such materials and Documentation. The following provisions survive the expiration or termination of this Agreement for any reason whatsoever: Disclaimers, Ownership, Limitations on Liability, Choice of Law and Forum, Entire Agreement and Severability.
12.	Choice of Law and Forum
This Agreement shall be governed in all respects under the laws of the State of Wisconsin, USA, exclusive of its choice of law or conflict of law provisions. In any claim or action by you directly or indirectly arising under this Agreement or related to the Service, you irrevocably agree to submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts located in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.
13.	Entire Agreement
This Agreement constitutes the entire agreement between you pertaining to the subject matter hereof. Anything contained in or delivered through the Service that is inconsistent with or conflicts with the terms of this Agreement is superseded by the terms of this Agreement. This Agreement may not be modified, in whole or in part, except as described elsewhere in this Agreement. This agreement may be superseded by any terms agreed between an individual and MCW.
14.	Severability
If any of the provisions of this Agreement are held to be not enforceable by a court or other tribunal of competent jurisdiction, then such provisions shall be amended, limited or eliminated to the minimum extent necessary so that this Agreement shall otherwise remain in full force and effect.
15.	Assignability
You agree that this Agreement and all incorporated agreements between you and us may be assigned by us, in our sole discretion to any third party.
16.	Contact Information
All notices to you relating to this Agreement shall be posted on the Service or sent to you at the email or physical address, if any, that you provided to us.
All notices to us relating to this Agreement may be made by email to: inventions@mcw.edu.
All technical inquiries relating to the Services under this Agreement may be made by email to: David.Sabsevitz@gmail.com
Notice shall be deemed given when notice is posted on the Service or when the email is sent, unless the sending party is notified that the email address is invalid.
Last updated: November 2018.
